

ENTHUSIASTIC SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CABA, Buenos Aires, Argentina

□ (+54) 911-6042-3765 | ■e@maraschio.com | # maraschio.com | □ emaraschio | □ emaraschio | ■ emaraschio | □ emaraschio

"A mind is like a parachute. It doesn't work if it is not open." - Frank Zappa

Summary.

I'm an Enthusiastic Software Developer from Buenos Aires with 10+ years of experience and I really enjoy to create things on the Web. I have been Developer, Scrum Master, Tech/Team Lead, Coach and Product Owner on a wide range of projects.

My goals are build the right thing, embrace the change and learn along the way within an exceptional Agile approach.

Specialities: Web Development, Agile Methodologies, Online Advertising, Product Development, Software Architecture

Work Experience

Thirty Madison Remote, USA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2018 - Present

- Web & Mobile Web Development using Ruby, TypeScript, Angular, React, HTML / HAML & CSS / SASS, Ruby on Rails, GraphQL, Cypress IO, PostgreSQL, Redis, Terraform, Docker among others.
- · Deploy solutions within AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Fargate, CloudFront) focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance and auto-scaling.

Manas Tech Remote, Argentina

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec 2017 - May 2018

- Web & Mobile Development for several clients using Ruby, Node.js, React / Redux, VueJS, Crystal, Elixir, HTML & CSS, Ruby on Rails, Phoenix, Selenium, PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ, Docker, Rancher among others.
- Deploy solutions within AWS (Rancher -> EC2, S3, CloudFront, RDS) focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance and auto-scaling.
- Agile Coaching & Training on several projects.

Deviget LLC Remote, USA / Argentina

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb 2012 - Sep 2017

- Web & Mobile Development for several clients using Ruby, Node.js, Angular, React, PHP, HTML & CSS, Ruby on Rails, Laravel, Selenium, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, CouchDB, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Docker, Vagrant among others.
- Deploy solutions within AWS (EC2, ECS, Route53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM) & Heroku, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance and auto-scaling.
- Agile Coaching & Training on several projects, from Scrum adoption to level-up Teams.

Zarego CABA, Argentina

Co-Founder & Software Engineer

Jul 2012 - Oct 2014

- Web & Mobile Development, MVP Development and Pre-Sales for several clients using Ruby, Node.js, Angular, PHP, HTML & CSS, Ruby on Rails, Symfony, Laravel, Selenium, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, CouchDB, MongoDB among others.
- Deploy solutions within AWS (EC2, ECS, Route53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM) focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance and auto-scaling.
- Scrum master and Owner of Agile Adoption & Training within Scrum Framework.

TeraCode SA CABA, Argentina

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2011 - Feb 2012

- Web Development for several clients using Ruby, PHP, Ruby on Rails, Symfony, HTML & CSS, MySQL, JS MVC, Selenium among others.
- Implemented overall application logic and wrote API services for high-availability Web apps.
- Agile Coaching & Training within Scrum Framework.

E-planning SACABA, Argentina

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & TEAM LEAD

Apr 2010 - May 2011

- · Web Development for an Ad-Server Product using PHP, Perl, HTML & CSS, MySQL, JS, Selenium among others.
- Implemented application logic and wrote API services for high-availability Ad-Server.
- Scrum master and Owner of Agile Adoption & Training within Scrum Framework.

Avatar SA CABA, Argentina

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar 2008 - Mar 2010

- Web Development for several clients using PHP, C#, ASP, Symfony, HTML & CSS, Selenium, MySQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, JS among others.
- Implemented overall application logic and wrote API services for high-availability Web apps.
- Agile practitioner within Scrum Framework.

Infocomercial SH CABA, Argentina

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar 2007 - Mar 2008

- Web Development for several clients using PHP, HTML & CSS, MySQL, JS among others.
- Implemented overall application logic and layouts for Web apps.
- · Technical support & assistance for several clients.

Public Speaking_

Speaker for <Full Stack Tech Conf AR 2nd Edition>

CABA, Argentina

FULL STACK TECH CONF: HTTPS://AR-FULLSTACK.TECH/

Nov 2017

• Workshop Fullstack End2End - Extended version: https://github.com/emaraschio/workshop-fullstack-conf-2017

Speaker for <Go Lang AR 2nd Meetup>

CABA, Argentina

GO LANG AR COMMUNITY GROUP: HTTPS://GOLANG.COM.AR/

Feb 2017

· Graphite with Go-Carbon

Speaker for < Rubysur Meetup>

CABA, Argentina

RUBYSUR COMMUNITY GROUP: HTTP://RUBYSUR.ORG/

July 2016

· Productivity Tips

Speaker for < Nerdearla 3rd Edition>

CABA, Argentina

NERDEARLA - FOR NERDS BY NERDS: HTTP://NERDEAR.LA/

June 2016

• How Web browsers works

Speaker for < Nerdearla 2nd Edition>

CABA, Argentina

NERDEARLA - FOR NERDS BY NERDS: HTTP://NERDEAR.LA/

June 2015

• Software Development Anti-Patterns

Speaker for < Nerdearla 1st Edition>

CABA, Argentina

NERDEARLA - FOR NERDS BY NERDS: HTTP://NERDEAR.LA/

March 2014

• Personal Organization Framework

Speaker for GULBAC Conf 1st Edition>

Mar del Plata, Argentina

GULBAC CONF: HTTPS://GULBAC.ORG/

June 2013

• Personal Organization Framework

• Scrum Inception

Education

Kleer CABA, Argentina

AGILE TEAM FACILITATOR (ATF)

Nov 2017

Scrum Alliance CABA, Argentina

CERTIFIED SCRUM PRODUCT OWNER (CSPO)

Sep 2013

Scrum Alliance CABA, Argentina

CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER (CSM)
Oct 2011

UAI CABA, Argentina

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Mar 2006 - Mar 2013

Unfinished

Languages_

Professional working proficiency

English

Native or bilingual proficiency

SPANISH